Young Master Han is loaded.
韓少君太有錢了
We have profited.
我們賺了
He's the hero.
這男主嘛
Of course he should be rich.
當然得有錢了
But it's only the tip of the iceberg.
不過這只是冰山一角
There is more to come.
厲害的還在後頭
What I mean is
我是說
Han Shuo is being gentle
韓爍現在這麼溫柔
like a kitty.
像只小貓咪一樣
A kitty wouldn't want to eat the orange.
貓咪總不會想吃橙子吧
Your Highness, you're really resourceful.
三公主謀略過人哪
This way,
那如此一來的話
Young Master Han will be devoted to you.
韓少君對你豈不死心又踏地呀
Zi Rui, let's enjoy opera songs at the tea house.
梓銳 咱倆茶館聽戲去
Your Highness, Young Master Han said,
公主 韓少君可說了啊
"If the Third Princess wants to listen to opera songs,
三公主想聽戲
invite the opera singers here from the theater."
我就去戲院把戲子請過來
Invite them here?
請過來
"If the Third Princess wants to eat dessert,
三公主想吃點心
ask a restaurant to make dessert and send it here."
我們就讓酒樓做好了送過來
Send it here?
送過來
"If the Third Princess wants to stroll on the streets,
三公主想逛大街
bring all the jugglers and stands in the city
我們就把城裡所有雜耍攤子
to the mansion."
全都搬到家裡來
In summary,
總之就一句話
stop the Third Princess from leaving the mansion.
讓三公主足不出戶
Stop me from leaving the mansion?
足不出戶
He wants to confine me to the mansion.
他這是想讓我大門不出二門不邁
Young Master Han is supporting the family, after all.
那現在不是韓少君養家嗎
It won't do.
那不能夠啊
Even my mother wouldn't confine me to the mansion
這母親都沒把我想圈在府裡
and stop me from going out.
不讓出去
Han Shuo wants to confine me?
韓爍想圈我
Not gonna happen.
不可能
He wants to trap me.
想困住我
Try it.
有這麼容易嗎
Your Highness, something seems wrong.
公主 情況好像有點不太對
It's her. It's her.
是她 是她
Do you sense a surge of hostility?
你有沒有感覺到一股殺氣
Now I know why Han Shuo
我知道韓爍為什麼
has been keeping me from leaving the mansion.
不讓我出門了
It's her, Chen Qianqian.
就是她陳芊芊
She destroyed our Dragon Bone.
破壞了我們的龍骨
Feudalistic superstition can cause great harm. Zi Rui.
封建迷信害死人 梓銳
She destroyed our Dragon Bone.
就是她破壞了我們的龍骨
Hit her! Hit her!
打她 打她
Run. Run.
跑 快跑
Hit her! Hit her! Hit her!
打她 打她 打她
The revised paragraph
剛才改的這一段
is a stroke of genius.
真是神來之筆呀
A desperate situation turned around.
置之死地而後生
I truly feel humbled.
小的實在是自愧不如
The orange's friendly gesture is precious and touching.
橙子情誼千金 感人肺腑
The banana should be too ashamed
香蕉
to ever attempt to harm the orange again.
恐怕也再也不好意思下毒手了
Moreover,
況且
the orange stepped out of the fight for succeeding the City Owner,
橙子退出了城主之爭
which gave way to the apple.
又給蘋果讓了路
It's killing three birds with one stone.
可謂是一箭三雕
No one died.
沒有死人
All problems have been solved.
所有問題都迎刃而解
Brilliant. Brilliant.
佩服 佩服
Don't you think
三位先生有沒有覺得
the orange is living
這橙子往後的日子
in a hostile environment?
生存環境很惡劣啊
Your Highness,
公主
Great people
成大事者
are always starved,
必先餓其體膚
poverty-stricken and exhausted
空乏其身 勞其筋骨
before finding happiness.
隨之才能苦盡甘來呀
Yeah.
是啊
Besides, seeing how smart you are,
況且 以三公主的智謀
the orange won't be stuck
橙子現在的窘況
in the difficult situation
也只是一時過渡
for too long.
不會太久
But the orange laid its hands
但 橙子此次動的
on the city's treasure.
可是鎮城之寶
Now the people are indignant.
現如今 民憤四起
I'm afraid the tension won't ease in a short time.
怕一時 難以平復
Can you please offer me some suggestions
三位先生就不能給出出主意
so I can improve the situation a little?
看看怎麼能稍微給改善改善
Unless
除非
another treasure appears,
天降第二件祕寶
otherwise...
否則
The idea of another treasure sounds good.
天降第二個祕寶也行
How often does a treasure appear?
祕寶多久降一次
Where can I find a treasure?
我從哪兒能找著
It won't take long.
不久
Just wait for over a thousand years.
也就 一千多年吧
Leave everything
就讓一切
to time.
都交給時間吧
This is my home.
這是我家啊
No matter what happens, I should be allowed to go home.
怎麼著我也不能不回家了吧
They think I can't do anything?
真是當我沒辦法了 是不是
Even a clay doll can have a fit.
這泥人尚且還有三分土性呢
Just because I'm not the Third Princess,
欺負我陳芊芊不是三公主
they think they can pick on me at will?
任人宰割了
Chen Qianqian!
陳芊芊
You jerk! Pig's ear!
你這個大渾蛋 豬耳朵
How dare you steal the Dragon Bone and bring bad luck to the city?
你居然敢偷龍骨破壞城運
What made you so bold?
誰給你這麼大膽
You had indulged in dissipation and you had been tyrannical.
你平時荒唐無度 暴虐成性
How dare you bring disaster to the people?
你今日竟然敢禍害百姓
Aren't you afraid of punishment from heaven?
你 你不怕天打雷劈嗎
Who is she?
她誰啊
You... You... I'm going to drag you out here
你 你 我今天就把你拖出來
and beat you up.
一頓暴打
I'll beat you up.
我就暴打我
Don't look at me. I'm shy. Don't look at me.
別 別看我 我害羞 別
I'll beat you up!
等我暴打你
She is Chen Qianqian!
她就是陳芊芊
Hit her! Hit her! Hit her!
打她 打她 打她
They blame me.
罵我
People block the door of Yueli Mansion.
百姓們紛紛自發堵在月璃府門口
They attack the Third Princess whenever they see her.
看見三公主就打
In the end, the Third Princess went back home
最後 還是三公主假裝路人
by pretending to be a passerby
自己罵自己
who scolded herself.
才進的門
She deserved it.
她真是活該
She had the nerve
居然膽大包天
to destroy the Dragon Bone for her own use.
將龍骨毀做私用
She acted against the people's will. She's definitely going to be punished.
真是倒行逆施 必遭天譴
Bad news. Bad news.
不好了 不好了
My lady,
小姐
the Dragon Bone has shown its presence and imposed punishment.
龍骨顯靈 降下天罰
Really? What happened to Chen Qianqian?
真的 陳芊芊她怎麼了
Lightning suddenly struck.
突降天雷
Our mine has exploded.
咱們家的礦被炸了
What?!
什麼
Whose mine has exploded?
誰家的礦被炸了
Ours.
咱家的
Our what has exploded?
咱家的什麼炸了
Mine.
礦啊
Say it again.
你再說一遍
What happened to our mine?
咱們家的礦怎麼了
It has exploded, my lady.
炸了 七小姐
Lightning has caused our mine to explode.
咱們家的礦被天雷給炸了
Explode. Explode. Explode.
炸了 炸了 炸了
Our mine has exploded?
咱們家的礦炸了
My lady, please make a decision right now.
小姐 你快拿個主意吧
Chen Qianqian,
陳芊芊
you jinx!
你這個災星
Heaven meant to punish you,
老天爺罰你
but lightning struck the wrong person's asset.
這雷還劈歪了
She has got her share of bad luck.
倒楣了吧
She always paraded her mine.
嘚瑟自己家裡有礦
Lightning struck it.
被雷劈了
Just because she was Huayuan City's moneybag,
仗著自己是花垣城的錢袋子
she tended to pick on you,
還喜歡欺負您
she tended to abuse her power.
還喜歡作威作福
Now I'd like to see her act tough.
我看她還怎麼硬氣
I'm here waiting for her.
我就在這兒等著她
She likes to pick on me, doesn't she?
不是愛找我碴嗎
Fine. Feel free to come at me.
儘管來 隨便來
Your Highness.
公主
Your Highness, I have bad news.
公主 大事不好了
More and more people have come to block the door.
圍在門口的百姓越來越多
They are going to barge into this place.
眼看就要闖進來了
Investigation shows the mine disaster wasn't caused by humans.
既然查清礦難之事並非人為
We should appease the families
那受困家屬的安撫之事
of the trapped miner properly.
也要妥善處理好
By the way,
對了
how is the rescue operation going?
解救之事 可有進展
The only escape for the trapped miners
被困礦工逃命的唯一通道
has been blocked by stones.
已經被亂石堵死
According to informed citizens,
據知情民眾交代
over 100 miners
這一百多名礦工
are trapped under the rear hill,
被困在山後的位置
not far from the earth's surface.
而且離地面不遠
If we use explosives to blast the rock,
若以火石炸開
we should be able to rescue the miners
我們應當能在礦洞完全坍塌之前
before the mine completely collapses.
將人救出
How many miners have been rescued?
那現在救出多少人了
We...
還
We haven't started the rescue operation yet.
還未施救
Outrageous.
荒唐
We are talking about over 100 lives.
這一百多條人命
Are you expecting me to rescue them personally?
莫非等著我親自去施救嗎
Your Majesty, please calm down.
城主息怒
It's not our intention to delay rescuing them.
並非我等刻意延誤救人時機
However...
只是
However, the mine's rear hill
只是這礦洞後山
is connected to Huayuan's fortune lode.
與我花垣福脈相連
If we use explosives,
一旦動用火石
the fortune lode will be affected.
福脈必受影響
We can't commit
如此罪責
such a sin, Your Majesty.
我等承擔不起啊 城主
Please think twice, Your Majesty.
城主三思啊
Huayuan has just lost the Dragon Bone.
花垣剛失龍骨
It must not lose the fortune lode.
萬不可再失福脈啊
A petition?
請願書
Your Majesty,
稟告城主
it's a petition submitted jointly by the citizens.
城內百姓共同上書
Ten thousand citizens have petitioned for...
萬民請願 請求
Petitioned for what?
請求什麼
Petitioned for...
請求
They have petitioned for Chen Qianqian's death to quell heaven's wrath.
請求賜死陳芊芊 以平天怒
How dare you!
放肆
Please sentence Chen Qianqian to death in order to quell heaven's wrath.
請賜陳芊芊一死 以平天怒
Your Highness.
三公主
Your Highness, please take pity on us.
三公主 可憐可憐我們
Save my son.
救救我兒子吧
And my family.
還有我的家人
All of them are buried in the mine.
都被埋在礦下
I don't know if they are alive or dead.
生死未卜啊
Over 100 lives
一百多條人命
depend on you.
全指望您了
They depend on you.
都指望您了
Is there anything I can do?
有什麼是我能夠做的嗎
Your Highness, I'm begging you,
求求三公主
please sacrifice yourself.
捨身取義
Offer yourself as a sacrifice to quell heaven's wrath.
祭天 平天怒吧
Please embrace death bravely, Your Highness.
求三公主英勇赴死
Please sacrifice yourself, Your Highness.
求三公主捨身祭天
Chen Qianqian calls herself the "Third Princess"
陳芊芊喊自己三公主
for fun.
只是為了好玩
But I'm the person to take the blame.
可我身為一個背鍋的
I'll pay a heavy price for this.
卻要因此付出很大的代價
Please sentence Chen Qianqian to death in order to quell heaven's wrath.
請賜陳芊芊一死 以平天怒
You...
你們
You are asking me to kill my child,
你們是要我殺了自己的孩子
aren't you?
是嗎
Now people are indignant.
如今民怨四起
We must kill her to assuage people's indignation.
不殺 不足以平民憤
Instead of trying to convict Chen Qianqian,
有想著如何定陳芊芊罪名的工夫
we should find a way
倒不如想想
to protect the fortune lode
既能保住福脈
and save lives.
又能救人的法子
Have you got any ideas, Minister Yang?
楊司戶有主意了
We can put the rescue operation on hold
不如先拖著
until the mine collapses.
拖到礦洞坍塌
Then we can declare the rescue team arrive too late,
對外宣稱援兵來遲
and pretend to scold the official
再對負責救援的大人
in charge of the rescue operation.
假意斥責一番
As for the families of the victims,
至於受難者的家屬
the government can appease them
讓衙門安撫安撫便是
with more financial compensation.
無非是多花些銀兩
What about Yueli Mansion?
那 月璃府呢
I heard people
聽聞百姓已將月璃府
have surrounded Yueli Mansion.
圍了個水洩不通
Chen Qianqian can neither enter nor leave the mansion.
陳芊芊進也不是 出也不是
She's in peril.
陷在危難之中
This matter
此事
requires your decision to settle.
還請城主拿個主意
Please give your order, mother.
請母親下令
What order?
下什麼令
The commoner Chen Qianqian laid her hands on the Dragon Bone
庶人陳芊芊擅動龍骨 惹來天罰
People have been punished for her crime. She must not be pardoned.
牽連蒼生 罪無可恕
I'd take troops to surround Yueli Mansion
女兒願親自帶兵圍困月璃府
and guard her well.
將她嚴加看守
After the storm calms down,
等事態平息
she will be dealt with according to her crime.
再論罪處置
Approved.
準了
You shall take troops there immediately.
即刻帶兵前往
Guard her well.
看好了她
Don't let that bastard run away.
勿叫這孽障跑了
Alright. You're dismissed.
好了 都散了吧
Mother.
母親
I'll keep Qianqian safe.
女兒定會護芊芊周全的
Chuchu.
楚楚
Qianqian has always been obedient to you.
芊芊一向最聽你的話了
Be on your way
你這次去
and don't let her run away.
千萬別讓她跑了
You must guard her well.
一定要看好了她
With you watching over her,
有你在
I'll feel relieved.
我也就放心了
Yes.
是
Chuchu.
楚楚
Whatever happens in the future,
不管將來任何時候
you must keep Qianqian safe.
你都要保護好芊芊
I won't fail you, mother.
女兒定不負母親所託
Your Majesty, it seems
看樣子 城主
you have high hopes for the Second Princess.
對二郡主還是寄予厚望
Qianqian is hopeless.
芊芊是個不成器的
I'm taking the overall situation into account,
我這也是以大局為重
leaving the important task to Chuchu.
將重任交與楚楚
I hope she'll achieve greatness
希望她將來爭氣些
and treat Qianqian nicely.
對芊芊 也會好一些
Qianqian,
芊芊
you and I are the children of City Owners.
你我同為城主之子
We seem to be in a high position,
看起來位高權重
but we often have no choice.
卻常常身不由己
Don't take their words to heart.
你別將他們的話放在心上
Just stay here.
就好好待在這裡
While I'm here,
有我在
nobody will dare to harm you.
沒人敢動你分毫
Bai Ji.
白芨
Tell our people to be on standby.
叫我們的人隨時待命
Yes.
是
I know I won't die.
我知道我死不了
But what about the miners in the mine?
可是礦裡的那些礦工怎麼辦
You're still thinking for them?
你還在替他們著想
Don't forget
你別忘了
that Huayuan's citizens
剛才花垣百姓
just petitioned for your sacrifice.
可是自發請願要你祭天
I'm Her Majesty's daughter.
我是城主的女兒
I enjoyed wealth in peaceful times.
平日裡享盡富貴
I didn't do much to benefit the people.
也沒做什麼好事造福百姓
All I did was make trouble.
整天還惹是生非的
It's normal
所以一有事情
for them to blame me
他們第一時間拿我開刀
when a disaster occurs.
也是正常
Mountains decide the scale of population and water decides the degree of prosperity.
山主人丁水主財
This place nestles against mountains and water.
此處依山傍水
It's a treasured land with great feng shui.
是塊風水絕佳的寶地
The so-called fortune lode was created
所謂福脈
when your ancestors settled down in this place.
就是先人在此處定居
Their descendants built a city
然後後人再以此處為中心
around this place.
在周圍建立城邦
Then Huayuan City gradually took form.
逐漸形成你們花垣城
This place has been honored as the fortune lode.
此地被尊稱為福脈
It's the foundation of Huayuan City.
是你們花垣城立城的根本
The fortune lode is very close to the mine,
福脈離礦山很近
because Huayuan City's economic lifeline
是因為你們花垣城的
lies in the mining industry.
經濟命脈是礦業
Your ancestors were really far-sighted.
你們先人還真是很有遠見
They built the city here
將城建在此處
to guarantee provisions for the citizens.
可保城民衣食無憂
My ancestors planned carefully,
祖先們千算萬算
but they didn't know they would have an unworthy descendant like me.
都沒算到有我這麼個不肖子孫
This place is connected to the mine.
此處與礦山相連相通
The drawing tells me
按圖紙看
those miners are trapped
那一百號人應該被困在
here.
此處
Before entering the cave and starting to mine,
礦工入洞挖礦之前
the miners would use pillars to secure the rocks in the cave,
會用柱子固定山洞的土石
preventing the mine from collapsing.
以防坍塌
From we are seeing now,
可是照現在這個情況上來看
only half of the mountain has collapsed,
山體只塌陷了一半
which means half of the wooden pillars
說明另外一半的木柱
are still supporting the cave.
仍然支撐著山洞
It's very likely that those people in the mine
那礦下面的人
will come out alive.
生還的可能性極大
The pillars in the mine
礦洞裡的柱子可能
might not hold for long.
支撐不了多久了
Then what are we waiting for? Go and rescue them now.
那還在等什麼 還不救人
Couldn't my mother and the others find a way out of this?
母親她們就一點辦法都沒有
I have an idea.
我倒是有個辦法
The fortune lode in the rear can be...
就是將後面的福脈給
Exploded.
炸了
Right.
對
You think so too?
少君也是這麼想的
Yes.
沒錯
This way, we can open up a path
這樣就能從後方開闢一條通道
for them to escape.
讓他們逃生
What's on your mind?
你在想什麼
I'm wondering
我在想
who would commit the monstrous crime
到底是誰願意去當這個千古罪人
of blowing up the fortune lode.
炸福脈
After I stewed the Dragon Bone,
我這把龍骨燉了
a bunch of people begged me to die.
一群人來求著讓我去死
Blowing up the fortune lode is also a grave crime that will result in capital punishment.
這炸福脈 也是大不敬的死罪
I know.
我知道了
Only one person can do this.
這個事情只有一個人能做
The heroine.
女主角
The heroine can do this for sure.
女主角一定能夠做
Qianqian.
芊芊
Make way.
你讓一下
Couldn't she see that I want to help her?
她是看不出我想幫她嗎
Young Master, you don't have to help her.
少君 您不出手也罷
It's unlikely for the miners to return alive.
如今這些礦工生還機會渺茫
The people will blame Her Majesty for her incompetence.
百姓定會怪城主無能
The more turbulent Huayuan City is,
花垣城局面越動盪
the more advantages Xuanhu City has.
對我們玄虎城就越有利
If you solve the problem,
萬一您出面解決了
you will fall into an awkward situation.
反倒處境尷尬呀
I'm afraid that the people
我是怕百姓把這筆賬
will blame Qianqian for this.
還是算在芊芊頭上了
But whatever.
也罷
She has thought of blowing up the fortune lode.
既然她也想到了炸福脈
As long as she can get out of her predicament,
只要能解她困境
it doesn't matter who will blow up the fortune lode.
誰炸都一樣
If the Third Princess will look for Minister Pei's help,
如若三公主要找的人是裴司學
will you be as open-minded as you are now?
少君還會這麼豁達嗎
Sure.
自然
Your Highness, where are you going?
三公主這是要去
I'm going to Chuchu.
找楚楚
Please don't make things difficult for us.
還請三公主不要為難小人
The Second Princess said
二郡主有命令 說
you must not leave the mansion.
不能讓三公主離開府門半步
But I will.
我就離開
Stop.
住手
Qianqian, you are so willful.
芊芊 你太任性了
We've given you everything you wanted since you were little.
自小我們什麼都依著你
Our pampering has made you what you are now,
才把你慣成如今這樣
a person who respects nothing.
天不怕地不怕的樣子
Chuchu,
二姐
we have an emergency. No time to dawdle.
現在情況緊急 來不及了
Take your troops to the mine
你趕緊帶你手下的人
and save over 100 miners.
去把礦場那一百多個人給救出來
Go now or it'll be too late.
晚了可就來不及了
We are talking about over 100 miners.
這可是一百多條人命
Other people can show no care,
別人可以漠不關心
but you can't. You are the heroine...
但你不行 你是女
I mean... the princess.
郡主
It's a good opportunity for you to win a reputation.
這是你刷名望的好機會
At this time,
都這個時候了
you're still thinking about those miners.
你還想著那些礦工
Just blow up the fortune lode
只要炸了福脈
and you'll be able to rescue all the miners.
就可以把人全部救出來了
Blow up the fortune lode?
炸福脈
You want me to end up
你是想讓我落得
like you?
跟你一樣的下場嗎
Be deposed by our mother.
被母親廢黜
Lose my princess's title.
失去郡主身份
Let people reproach me and petition for my sacrifice?
被萬民痛罵 請願祭天嗎
That's different.
那 那能一樣嗎
I stole the Dragon Bone to satisfy my selfish desire.
我偷龍骨那是為了一己私慾
You won't do the same thing.
你不一樣啊
If you blow up the fortune lode,
炸掉福脈
our mother will flare up for a moment,
雖然會引得母親一時發怒
but you will save the people
但是你救了黎民百姓
and win people's hearts.
贏得的是民心
People's hearts are more important
民心當然比母親的喜怒
than mother's mood.
更加重要呀
For you,
對你而言
people's hearts are no doubt more important.
民心當然更重要
Because you are already loved by mother.
那是因為你深得母親寵愛
You know what,
你知不知道
when I was fighting in other places
我在外與人搏命
and facing danger,
危在旦夕的時候
mother stayed by your bed
母親卻守在你的床前
and took no interest in my situation.
對我不聞不問
Just then,
剛剛
she finally smiled at me.
母親終於對我笑了
Do you know why?
你知道為何
Because I asked to guard you with troops.
卻是因為我請命要帶兵護著你
Mother only cares about you.
在母親的眼裡她只有你
But again and again, you have done things
但你卻一再做出
to place her in a dilemma.
讓她進退兩難的事
Chuchu.
二姐
Has it ever occurred to you
你可曾想過
that if I had been the person who stole the Dragon Bone,
如果當初動龍骨的人是我
I might have
我現在
died now?
或許已經是一具屍體了
That's not true, Chuchu.
不是這樣的 二姐
You would have followed heaven's will if you had stolen the Dragon Bone.
你動龍骨那是順應天命
And I only stole the Dragon Bone to...
我動龍骨只是為了
Never mind.
罷了
... save my life.
保命
I'll just guard you well
我只將你看管妥當
and save myself from our mother's reprimand.
不被母親責罵便好
Chuchu.
二姐
You'll be the future City Owner.
你是將來要繼任城主的人
How can you give up over 100 lives
你怎麼可以為了逃避母親的責罵
to avoid mother's reprimand?
就放棄一百多條生命呢
Is your reputation as a princess
郡主的名聲
more important than over 100 lives?
真的比一百多條生命還重要嗎
I can't destroy the fortune lode for them.
我不可能為了他們毀掉福脈
For those miners,
至於那些礦工
sacrificing themselves for Huayuan City
為花垣城犧牲
is their privilege
也算是他們作為
as Huayuan's citizens.
花垣子民的福分了
Qianqian, I hope
芊芊 希望經此一事
you'll consider others more from now on.
以後你也能多為別人著想
Keep your nose clean.
安分守己一點吧
If you hadn't stolen the Dragon Bone,
如果當初你沒有動龍骨
maybe mother would have ordered people
說不定母親今天就會下令
to blow up the fortune lode
動一動福脈
and rescue the miners.
救下那些人
Escort her back to her room.
帶她回房間
But if I had behaved,
可我如果安分守己
I might have died already.
也許早死了幾百回了
Qianqian,
芊芊
you have failed to get Chuchu's help.
你向楚楚求助無果
Try to seek help from someone else.
不如再 想想別人
Someone else?
別人
Who can help me now?
現在誰還能幫我啊
Try to rely on men.
不如試著 依靠一下男人
Men?
男人
You mean...
難道
Find Pei Heng.
去找裴恆
Your Highness.
三公主
I've been told that you're ill.
聽說你身體不適
What's the problem?
哪裡不舒服
Why didn't you have Princess Royal diagnose you?
怎麼不請大郡主為你診治
No.
沒有
I'm not ill. I lied to you.
我沒生病 我是騙你的
I have invited you here today to ask for a favor.
我今天請你來是有事相求
I want to leave the mansion.
我想出府
Since you don't want to stay here,
既然你不願待在這裡
I'll take you out.
我便帶你出去
I knew you would help me.
我就知道你一定會幫我
She would rather ask Pei Heng for help than ask me.
求裴恆都不求我
Pei Heng can't carry heavy loads.
裴恆他肩不能扛 手不能提
He has no troop to command.
麾下也沒有一兵一卒
What can he do?
他能幹成什麼呀
Young Master,
少君
you said as long as the Third Princess could get out of her predicament,
您不是說只要能解三公主的困境
it didn't matter who would blow up the fortune lode.
福脈誰炸不都一樣嗎
It didn't matter?
誰炸都一樣
I'd like to see
我倒要看看
how can they explode the fortune lode
沒有我
without my help.
這福脈如何炸得
Your Highness.
二郡主
What are you...
你這是
I heard Qianqian is ill.
聽說芊芊身子不舒服
I told the kitchen staff to cook her favorite food.
我叫廚房做了些她愛吃的
Your Highness,
二郡主
the Third Princess has gone to bed.
我們三公主已經歇下了
It's inconvenient for her to meet you now.
恐怕不太方便見您
Maybe you should leave.
要不 您請回
What? But Minister Pei just left.
怎麼 裴司學不是才剛走
She is already in bed now?
這麼快就歇下了
Yeah. The Third Princess is feeling dizzy.
是啊 我們三公主頭暈眼花
I think she has gone to bed.
應該睡下了
She must be angry with me.
她是在生我氣吧
Qianqian,
芊芊
I know my harsh words have hurt your feelings.
我知道我剛才說重話傷了你的心
Don't be mad.
你不要生氣
I was just having a fit.
我也只是一時心急
I'm keeping you indoors for your own good.
我不讓你出去也是為了你好
The outside world is turbulent.
現在外面動盪不安
Everyone is looking to condemn you.
人人都要拿你問罪
Mother and I have no choice
我和母親
but to make such an unfortunate decision.
只有出此下策
Stop being mad.
你別慪氣了
Have some food.
先吃點東西吧
Qianqian.
芊芊
Your Highness, uh...
二郡主 那個
Your Highness, spare me.
二郡主 饒命啊
You are a servant from Pei Heng's mansion.
你是裴恆府上的小廝
So dizzy.
好暈
What a cunning escape plan.
好一個金蟬脫殼
Didn't she think of my situation before running away?
她跑之前就不想想我的處境嗎
I'm finally out.
總算是逃出來了
Your mansion has become a target of public criticism.
你的府邸已成眾矢之的
Come with me to my mansion.
你隨我回府
Nobody will dare to harm you there.
沒有人敢傷害你
No. I must go to the mine.
不行 我得去礦場
You asked me to take you out,
你要我帶你出來
so you could rescue those miners?
是為了救那些礦民
Yes.
對呀
How are you going to rescue them?
如何救
Blow up the fortune lode.
炸福脈
Have you thought of the consequences?
你 你可想過炸福脈的後果
Now the officials,
如今上到議事官員
peddlers and dogsbodies
下到販夫走卒
wish to sacrifice you to assuage the people's indignation.
都要你祭天以平民憤
If you blow up the fortune lode,
若你再炸了福脈
things will get worse.
情況只會更糟
Even Her Majesty might not be able to save you,
到時候別說是我
not to mention me.
可能連城主都保不了你
But...
可是
Success hinges on human efforts.
事在人為
If you never try, you'll never know.
你不試試怎麼知道結果呀
We are talking about over 100 lives, after all.
畢竟是一百多條人命
It's nothing to joke about.
這可不能開玩笑
But the miners
可那些礦民
are all men.
都是男子
Men and women
男子與女子
aren't different in essence.
本質上本來就沒有什麼不同
They are all human lives.
都是人命
I didn't know you held this kind of opinion.
你竟這樣想
Please turn into that alley ahead.
麻煩幫我拐進前面巷子裡
Pei Heng.
裴恆
Zi Rui and I agreed to meet at the mine.
我跟梓銳約好了在礦場見面
I have to rush there.
我得趕緊趕過去了
Qianqian.
芊芊
I'm going with you.
我陪你一起去
I can't let you dive into danger alone.
我不能看著你隻身犯險
No need, Pei Heng.
不用了 裴恆
I can't get you in trouble.
我不能連累你了
I'm already in trouble, so I'm not afraid.
我這是蝨子多了不怕咬
But you should stay out of it.
你就不要惹火上身了
Got to go. Thank you.
走了 謝謝
Qianqian. Qianqian.
芊芊 芊芊
I've failed you.
女兒無能
Qianqian has run away.
三妹她 跑了
You...
你
Why didn't you dodge?
你為何不躲
What? The Third Princess has gone to the mine?
什麼 三公主去礦場了
But...
這
Come on. I'm going to the mine.
走 我要去礦場
Mother.
母親
Does mother
母親心中
only care about Qianqian?
就只有芊芊嗎
Your Highness.
郡主
What should we do now?
那我們現在該怎麼辦
Please give an order.
您快拿個主意
Inform the City Guards
通知護城軍
to come with me to Lin's mine.
隨我去林家礦場
Yes.
是
Are our people in place?
我們的人就位了嗎
Our people are in place,
我們的人已經就緒
making sure the Third Princess won't be harmed.
謹防有人傷害三公主
But Young Master,
可是少君
Minister Pei will have people
裴司學肯定會派人
help the Third Princess rescue the miners.
幫助三公主救人
Why are we waiting here?
我們還在這兒等什麼呢
Pei Heng can't help Qianqian.
裴恆幫不了芊芊
What does a person need
想要炸福脈
to blow up the fortune lode?
關鍵是什麼
The fortune lode.
福脈
What else?
除了福脈呢
Explosives.
炸藥
She will beg me eventually.
她總有求我的時候
Xuanhu City
我們玄虎城
uses black stones to make explosives.
將烏石製成炸藥
Huayuan City uses black stones to make fireworks.
他們花垣城將烏石製成煙花
What's the use of fireworks?
煙花能成什麼事
Have you got everything ready?
準備好了嗎
I have got everything ready.
都準備好了
Good.
好
We have no explosives.
沒有炸藥
How am I going to blow up the fortune lode without explosives?
沒有炸藥我拿什麼炸福脈
Can I use you to blow it up?
我拿你炸
Should I use you to blow it up?
我是不是拿你炸我
Huayuan City has always produced nothing but fireworks.
我們花垣城自古以來只做煙花呀
Only Xuanhu City produces explosives.
玄虎城才做炸藥啊
Right. Han Shuo nearly destroyed Huayuan
對了 韓爍後來就是靠炸藥
with explosives in the later stages.
險些滅了花垣
Come on.
過來
Who owns explosives in Huayuan City?
花垣城現在誰還有炸藥
Who?
誰
The Second Princess.
二郡主
The Second Princess is also the Minister of Defense.
二郡主兼任司軍
She definitely owns explosives.
她手裡肯定有炸藥
If Chuchu sees me,
我去求楚楚
she'll catch me and send me back to the mansion before I could ask her for explosives.
還沒開口就被她抓回府中了
Minister Pei.
裴司學
Minister Pei is the only son of the late Minister of Defense Pei.
裴司學是已故裴司軍的獨子
If he asks the City Guards for help, they will do him a favor.
他去求護城軍 肯定能成
Minister Pei never intervenes
裴司學從來不插手
in the City Guards' affairs.
護城軍的軍內事務
I can't trouble him.
我不能麻煩他
Lin Qi.
林七
She is the richest person in Huayuan City.
她可是花垣城的首富
She can purchase explosives at a high price.
她能高價購買
Yeah.
是啊
Lin Qi can spend a lot of money
讓林七花高價
on explosives to blow up her own mine.
自己買炸藥炸了自己的礦
Between Lin Qi and you,
你跟林七總有一個人
one of you must have been brain-damaged.
腦子被炸過了你們倆
What's wrong with them?
你說說他們啊
They even considered seeking Lin Qi's help.
連林七都想到了
You simply never crossed their minds.
就是想不到你
This is...
這
an emergency.
情況緊急
It's inevitable for them to neglect the obvious.
難免有些 疏忽
I'm going to kick you to death.
我踹死你
No. Give me more time to think.
別 你再讓我想想吧
Who is there?
誰
A bamboo tube.
竹筒
Fireworks.
煙花
I got it!
我想到了
Finally.
終於
The owner of the grocery shop.
雜貨鋪老闆
Han Shuo, what brought you here?
韓爍 你怎麼來了
I'm just passing by.
我路過
We heard
那個 你們剛才說的
what you said.
我們都聽見了啊
You are really thoughtful.
三公主還真是思慮周全啊
You have considered seeking help from everyone in Huayuan City.
把花垣城上上下下的人都想到了
But I don't know anyone
就是沒想到一個
who can give me explosives.
能給我搞炸藥的人
Our Young Master is standing right before you.
就我們少君就站在你面前
Can't you see?
你看不見嗎
I'll be in the toilet.
我上個茅房
Han Shuo.
韓爍
Right. Xuanhu City produces explosives.
對啊 玄虎城擅制火藥
But will you help me?
可你能幫我嗎
We are on different sides.
咱倆立場不同
I understand your doubts.
我明白三公主疑慮
But this is a life-and-death matter. It's an emergency.
但人命關天 情況緊急
I won't gamble on human lives.
我不會拿人命來博弈
A life-and-death matter?
人命關天
It turns out Han Shuo
原來韓爍根本就不是
isn't as cold and heartless as I thought.
我想的那樣冷酷無情
This is what a hero should look like.
這才是男主角該有的樣子嘛
What is a hero?
什麼是男主角
It's like the male lead of a story.
就是戲本里的大英雄
Then can the hero
那 大英雄能
win the beauty's heart?
抱得美人歸嗎
He usually can as long as he doesn't die.
只要不死的話 一般都能
Fortunately,
幸好
my heart disease has been cured by you.
韓某心疾已被三公主治癒
Don't worry.
你放心
I have planted the explosives.
炸藥我已經安置好了
The explosives can be detonated anytime.
隨時可以引爆
It's dangerous.
危險
Let me go.
我去
No. I should go.
不是 當然是我去啊
You can't go.
你怎麼能去
You are the precious Third Princess.
三公主是千金之軀
You'll regain your title sooner or later.
遲早會恢復身份
You had better be careful.
還是慎重些
I'll go in your stead.
我替你去
No.
不行
You are the beloved son of the owner of Xuanhu City.
少君是玄虎城城主的愛子
You'll achieve greatness in the future.
將來勢必是大有作為
How can you take such a risk for me?
怎麼能為我去承擔這樣的風險
Of course I should go.
當然是我去
I said I'd let no harm come to you.
我說我定不會傷你一分一毫
It's so dangerous.
如此危險
I should go.
還是我去吧
Young Master, you don't know
少君 你不明白你的命
how important you are to me.
對於我來說有多麼重要
If anything happens to you, the whole situation will change.
你可是動一髮而牽動全身
No. You can't go. I'll go.
不行 你不能去 我去
But without you,
但是沒有你
my life would have no meaning.
我的命還有什麼意義
Then...
那
Then we can go together.
那我們一起去
Okay.
好
Qianqian.
芊芊
Have I blown the right structure?
我炸的位置對嗎
Step back.
你退後點
Step back further.
再往後
What is the meaning of this?
少君這是何意呀
You sprinkled dust
灰塵
on the Third Princess.
沾到三公主身上了
Come on.
走
Qianqian.
芊芊
Hurry.
快
Chen Qianqian!
陳芊芊
Isn't this Lin Qi?
這不林七嗎 這不
Are you here to help? Let's do it together.
來 來幫忙的 一起吧
Chen Qianqian,
陳芊芊
you not only disbanded my Music and Dance Academy,
你遣散我的教坊司還不夠
but also blew up my black stone mine.
居然還炸了我家的烏石礦
I even blew up the fortune lode.
福脈我都炸了
Who cares about your mine?
我還管你家礦
How funny.
有趣
I'll teach you a lesson today!
今天我一定要讓你好看
Get her!
給我上
Stop. Stop.
住手 住手
You're defending her again?
你又包庇她
Your people
你的人
are no match for my guards.
肯定不是裴府侍衛的對手
Leave.
散了吧
Stop!
住手
Arrest the criminal
將損毀福脈的罪魁禍首
who destroyed the fortune lode!
給我拿下
Your Highness,
二郡主
you also want to capture Qianqian?
你也要捉拿芊芊
Minister Pei,
裴司學
I'm afraid your guards
你的人
are no match for the City Guards.
恐怕不是護城軍的對手吧
Arrest her.
拿下
Stop!
住手
I pay respect to you, Your Majesty.
參見城主
What,
怎麼
are you going to arrest
你要把你妹妹
your younger sister as if she is a criminal?
當成罪人一樣抓起來嗎
Chen Qianqian blew up the fortune lode.
陳芊芊炸燬福脈
She must not be exempted from punishment.
罪無可恕
Please punish her, Mother.
請母親降罰
Outrageous!
大膽
How can you?
你怎麼能
How dare you?
你怎麼敢
Don't worry.
你放心
My people have always been around.
我的人一直都在
I will keep you safe.
定護你周全
How many troops have you deployed here secretly?
你一共埋伏了多少人馬呀
The whole crew must be here.
全劇組的人都來了吧
This must be a big scene. Gosh.
大場面呀 我的天
I have never written such a costly scene.
我還沒寫過這麼燒錢的戲呢
We have found them! We have found them!
挖到了 挖到了
Come and rescue them!
快來救人哪
Coming!
來了
Be careful. Be careful. Be careful.
慢點慢點 慢點
Here. Be careful.
來 慢點
Here.
來
Be careful. Be careful.
慢點 慢點
Come on. Sit down.
來 來來來 坐下
Is anyone left down there?
下面還有人嗎
No. No one.
沒 沒了
Everyone has been taken out.
都被救出來了
Qianqian.
芊芊
Are you okay?
沒事吧
You are...
你是
The Third... Third Princess.
三 三公主
How come you...
你 你怎麼
The Third Princess saved you.
三公主救了你們
The Third Princess.
三公主
Thank you, Your Highness.
多謝你 三公主
No! The fortune lode is gone!
不好 福脈 福脈沒了
Your Majesty.
城主
Chen Qianqian destroyed the Dragon Bone for her selfish interests earlier.
陳芊芊先是因為私心毀掉了龍骨
Now she blown up the fortune lode without permission.
今天又擅作主張地炸了福脈
Huayuan City's long-standing business
我花垣城的世代基業
has been ruined by her.
皆毀於她一人之手
Your Majesty, please sentence Chen Qianqian to death.
請城主 賜死陳芊芊
Your Majesty.
城主
The Dragon Bone and fortune lode
龍骨和福脈
have decided Huayuan City's fate for about a thousand years.
關係到我花垣城千年的氣運
Chen Qianqian must die,
若是想要饒了陳芊芊的性命
unless Huayuan City obtains another treasure.
除非 花垣城再降珍寶
How dare you!
大膽
Your Majesty, please listen to the citizens.
城主 請順應民意呀
Your Majesty, please sentence Chen Qianqian to death.
城主 請賜死陳芊芊
Your Majesty.
城主
please pardon the Third Princess.
請赦免三公主
The Third Princess is kind-hearted.
三公主有仁心
She loves people as if they are her children.
愛民如子啊
Your Majesty.
城主
Please pardon the Third Princess.
請赦免三公主
Chen Qianqian must not be exempted from punishment,
若想讓陳芊芊脫罪
unless another treasure shows up
除非再降珍寶
to fill in for the lost Dragon Bone and fortune lode.
彌補龍骨和福脈的缺憾
Otherwise, our ancestors
否則 列祖列宗
won't rest in peace.
不得安息
You have me.
有我在
Don't be afraid.
別怕
For unlucky people,
這都說人倒黴的時候
everything can be a torment.
喝涼水都塞牙
But for lucky people,
但人走起運來
things can always take a turn for the better.
撿張廢紙都能當錢使
Lin Qi,
林七
look what this is.
你看這是什麼
The fire box.
火匣子
Petroleum! Petroleum!
猛火油 猛火油
Petroleum!
猛火油
It's petroleum.
是猛火油
It's true that the black stone mine is the foundation of Huayuan City.
花垣城立城之本是烏石礦不假
But petroleum
可這猛火油
is even more precious than the black stone mine.
可比烏石礦更為金貴吧
Yes.
是啊
Petroleum is also known as black water.
這猛火油又稱黑水
One cubic meter of black water is worth more than one dou of gold.
區區一方 便勝鬥金
From what we are seeing now,
照現在這情形來看
enormous wealth is buried
福脈之下
under the fortune lode.
確有千秋萬代的財富
The fact that the Third Princess risked her life to save the miners
是三公主冒死救人
has touched her ancestors. They have bestowed this treasure on us.
感動先祖 降下福祉
The Third Princess has unearthed the black water mine.
三公主挖出了黑水礦
Heaven has blessed us
天降黑水礦
with the black water mine.
佑我花垣城
Can you hear what they are calling you?
你聽他們叫你什麼
The Third Princess.
三公主啊
In the past, they called you the Third Princess
往日眾人喚你三公主
to taunt you, and mostly, to tease you.
三分奚落 七分戲謔
But now they are calling you the Third Princess
可今日眾人喚你三公主
to show submission, and mostly, to revere you.
三分臣服 七分敬畏
Heaven has blessed us with the black water mine.
天降黑水礦 佑我花垣城
You deserve the title of the Third Princess.
你當得起三公主
Heaven has blessed us
佑我花垣城
with the black water mine.
天降黑水礦
It'd take more than a thousand years
石油的形成
for petroleum to take form.
何止是千年
It'd take a million years.
是需要百萬年
As they said,
果然
time can solve every problem.
時間可以解決一切的事情
Heaven has blessed us with the black water mine.
天降黑水礦 佑我花垣城
Your Majesty,
稟告城主
the black water mine is extremely rare.
黑水礦萬萬年難遇一次
I only heard of it from legends.
下官只在傳說中聽過
Its value is even greater than the Dragon Bone.
其價值更甚龍骨
It'll be very conducive to stabilizing the city
這對穩固城邦 造福百姓
and benefiting the people.
大有裨益
We can expect the city to prosper soon.
城富民強 指日可待
All this
這一切
is the result of the Third Princess's good fortune.
都是三公主帶來的福氣呀
Chen Qianqian has become a commoner.
陳芊芊早已是庶民身份
She is not the Third Princess.
可不是什麼三公主
Her Majesty's fortune is people's fortune.
城主之福便是百姓之福
Now everyone is commending the Third Princess
如今人人稱頌三公主
for blowing up the fortune lode and saving the people.
炸福脈 救黎民
The black water mine shows our ancestors' approval of the Third Princess.
黑水礦就是先祖對三公主的肯定
Your Majesty,
下官奏請城主
please restore the Third Princess's title
立即恢復三郡主身份
to show your benevolence and grace.
以示城主德重恩弘
Your Majesty.
城主
Alright.
好了
Minister Yang is right.
楊司戶所言極是
Qianqian has made a great contribution.
芊芊立下大功一件
Her title shall be restored immediately.
即刻恢復她的郡主身份
You're wise, Your Majesty.
城主英明
Your Highness, what would you like to eat today?
三公主 今天您想吃點什麼
Delicacies of all kinds. I'll eat anything expensive.
山珍海味 什麼貴我吃什麼
Yes.
是
-Your Highness? -Your Highness!
三公主 三公主
Your Highness.
三公主
Stop! Don't run.
站住 你別跑啊
Hurry. Hurry. Hurry.
快 快 快
I have got my title back.
我都已經恢復公主身份了
Why are they still chasing me?
她為什麼還要追我
We have no guard. We must run.
咱身邊也沒侍衛 不跑不行啊
Han Shuo.
韓爍
Wait.
等等
Your Highness, why are you running?
三公主 你跑什麼呀
If I didn't run, you'd hit me.
我不跑 我等著你們砸我啊
Those tomatoes are really big.
今天西紅柿還挺大
Yeah.
對呀
Your Highness, you are mistaken.
三公主 您誤會了
These are our gifts for you.
這些都是我們送給您的
Your Highness.
三公主
We are sorry for being rude to you the other day.
之前是我們不好 衝撞了您
My eldest brother worked at Lin's mine.
我大哥是林家礦上的
When I heard of the mine disaster,
聽說發生了礦難
I thought I would never see him again.
我以為再也見不到他了
Young Master Han and you rescued him.
是你和韓少君把他救了出來
Thank you.
謝謝你們啊
Yes. Yes.
是 是
It's okay. No trouble. No trouble at all.
沒事 舉手之勞 舉手之勞
You risked your lives to save them.
你冒死救人
We can never pay you back.
我們也沒什麼好報答您的
These eggs
這些呀
are laid by our hens.
都是我們自己家老母雞下的蛋
And we grew these vegetables.
這都是我們自己種的
All these things are for you.
送給您 送給您
Let me do it.
我來吧
These things
這些啊
are far more delicious than the delicacies.
可比山珍海味好吃多了
That's right.
那是
Thank you.
謝謝